

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · MATHEMATICIAN

852 Centerwood Drive, Charleston, SC 29412

□ (631) 291-3866 | **Sam.chong.tay@gmail.com** | **Samtay** | **Sam.tay** | **Sam.ta**

Summary _

Skillful problem solver with a background in pure mathematics. 2+ years experience in web development, backend/infrastructure, and devops. Proven ability to quickly ramp up on new languages/technologies. Efficiency nerd who loves Vim, Linux, and xmonad, and enjoys customizing the development environment. Interested in learning new technologies and tools to solve complex, challenging problems.

Experience _____

Blue Acorn Charleston, SC

SENIOR APPLICATIONS ENGINEER

May 2014 - Feb 2017

- Streamlined deployment pipeline across the organization.
- · Pushed the most contributions to internal modules.
- Improved developer experience via Tampermonkey scripts and zsh plugins.
- Achieved the most "Play of the Sprint" awards in 2015.
- · Promoted from Apprentice to Senior within two years for exemplary work quality and productivity.

SIB Development & Consulting

Charleston, SC

REPORTING ANALYST

Sep 2013 - May 2014

· Contributed to unclogging the largest bottleneck in company operations, using Acrobat and Excel.

AstroParticule et Cosmologie

Paris, France

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Summer 2011

 Conducted research and data analysis in correlation of temperature variation and phase noise for LOT (LISA On Table), an optical simulator for the LISA mission, under Dr. Hubert Halloin.

Valparaiso University Valparaiso, IN

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Summer 2010

 Explored pattern avoidance in ternary trees (combinatorial mathematics) in a team of three undergraduate students under mentor Dr. Lara Pudwell.

Skills

• Agile experience in both scrum and kanban, along with Jira, Workfront, and ZenHub.

Development

- Experience leading an agile team and mentoring junior developers.
- Very efficient workflow from requirements gathering to development execution.
- Experience with direct client interactions and discussing complex technological details with nontechnical stakeholders.

Languages

- Fluent in PHP, Javascript, and C++.
- Experience with Haskell, Bash, Python, C.

Software

- · Mastery of Magento.
- Experience with technologies such as Docker, Ansible, NodeJS, Symfony, MySQL, RabbitMQ.

Workflow

- · Proficient in Linux and MacOS.
- Enjoy maximizing productivity with development tools such as git, vim, tmux, xmonad, zsh, and ngrok.

Education

Kenyon College Gambier, OH

B.S. IN MATHEMATICS AND SCIENTIFIC COMPUTING

Sep 2009 - May 2013

Awarded Distinction on Senior Thesis
Achieved GPA of 3 91

Publications

Pattern Avoidance in Ternary Trees

Journal of Integer Sequences

Dec 2011

Nathan Gabriel, Katherine Peske, Lara Pudwell, and Samuel Tay http://arxiv.org/abs/1110.2225

MARCH 8, 2017 SAMUEL C. TAY · RÉSUMÉ